Guide to the Filmer Stuart Cuckow Northrop Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- PROFESSIONAL PAPERS, 1916-1976; Series I; 5 linear feet (11 boxes)
  - Notes and Lectures
    - Notes: European Coal and Steel Community, 1952 (Box 10, Folder 253)
    - Notes: on European politics, 1952 (Box 10, Folder 254)
    - Notes: conversation with Werner Heisenberg, 1956 (Box 10, Folder 255)
    - Notes: East-West Philosophers Conference, [1959?] (Box 10, Folder 256)
    - Notes: legal theory seminar, [ca.1961] (Box 10, Folder 257)
    - Notes: from lecture on western music, 1962 (Box 10, Folder 258)
    - Notes: on dance, 1965 (Box 10, Folder 259)
    - Notes: booklets on corporation law, 1965-1967 (Box 10, Folder 260-262)
    - Notes: for book on corporations, 1966-1967 (Box 10, Folder 263)
    - Notes: on music, 1967 (Box 11, Folder 264)
    - Notes: conference with Donald Andrews, 1970 (Box 11, Folder 265)
    - Notes: on music, 1970 (Box 11, Folder 266)
    - Lectures: legal theory seminar, undated (Box 11, Folder 267)
    - Lectures: outline and cases for Philosophy 10a, undated (Box 11, Folder 268)
    - Lectures: India, undated (Box 11, Folder 269)
    - Notes: ancient philosophy, undated (Box 11, Folder 270)
    - Notes: conference with Lars Orsager, undated (Box 11, Folder 271)
    - Notes: cosmology and relativity, undated (Box 11, Folder 272)
    - Notes: logic, undated (Box 11, Folder 273-274)
    - Notes: Newtonian mechanics, undated (Box 11, Folder 275)
    - Notes: on paper of Joseph C. Smith, undated (Box 11, Folder 276)
    - Notes: on Petzoldt's Maxima, Minima and Economy, undated (Box 11, Folder 277)
    - Notes: philosophy, undated (Box 11, Folder 278)
    - Notes: philosophy of science, undated (Box 11, Folder 279)
    - Notes: philosohpy of science and modern science, undated (Box 11, Folder 280)
    - Notes: philosophy 10a (logic), undated (Box 11, Folder 281)
    - Notes: Sixth International Congress of Philosophy, undated (Box 11, Folder 282)
- WRITINGS, 1926-1979; Series II; 2.25 linear feet (6 boxes)
  Series II has two sections; Books and Articles. Books, Boxes 12-13, contain typescripts for three books and illustrations for one. Boxes 14-17 contain Articles. The material is arranged in chronological and then alphabetical order.
  - Books
    - The Meeting of East and West, 1946 (Box 12, Folder 283-294)
    - The Meeting of East and West: illustrations, 1946 (Box 13, Folder 295-296)
      See also: box 46, folder 990
    - Logic of the Sciences and Humanities, 1947 (Box 13, Folder 297-300)
    - Man, Nature and God, 1962 (Box 13, Folder 301-304)
  - Articles
    - Partial bibliography of Northrop's writings, Circa1953 (Box 14, Folder 305)
    - "Value of Philosophy to Scientific and Literary Students", 1926 (Box 14, Folder 306)
    - "The Theory of Relativity and the First Principles of Science", 1928 (Box 14, Folder 307)
    - "A Reply (to A.P. Uchenko's criticism of Northrop's article on Aristotelian logic) Emphasizing the Existential Import of Propositions", 1929 (Box 14, Folder 308)
    - "Concerning the Philosophical Consequences of the Theory of Relativity", 1930 (Box 14, Folder 309)
    - Review of The Mysterious Universe: by Sir James Jeans, 1930 (Box 14, Folder 310)
    - "The Body-Mind Problem," review of: Beyond Physics by Sir Oliver Lodge, 1931 (Box 14, Folder 311)
    - "Religion Must Face Metaphysics," review of: The Dilemma of Religious Knowledge by Charles A. Bennett, 1931 (Box 14, Folder 312)
    - Review of: The Academy for Souls by John O'Hara Cosgrove, 1931 (Box 14, Folder 313)
    - Review of: Beyond the Sublime Porte by Barnette Miller, 1931 (Box 14, Folder 314)
    - Review of: Reason and Nature: An Essay on the Meaning of Scientific Method by Morris R. Cohen, 1931 (Box 14, Folder 315)
    - "Evolution and the Flux of Forms", 1932 (Box 14, Folder 316)
    - Review of: Science and Human Experience by Herbert Dingle, 1932 (Box 14, Folder 317)
    - Review of: The Universe in the Light of Modern Physics by Max Planck, 1932 (Box 14, Folder 318)
    - "Adventurous Philosophy," review of: Adventures in Ideas by Alfred North Whitehead, 1933 (Box 14, Folder 319)
    - "The History of Modern Physics in its Bearing Upon Biology and Medicine", 1938 (Box 14, Folder 320)
    - "Evidence for the Existence of an Electro-Dynamic Field in Living Organisms," with H.S. Burr, 1939 (Box 14, Folder 321)
    - "The Significance of Epistemic Corrections in Scientific Method", 1939 (Box 14, Folder 322)
    - "Whitehead's Philosophy of Science", 1941 (Box 14, Folder 323)
    - "The Criterion of the Good State", 1942 (Box 14, Folder 324)
    - "The Meaning of Western Civilization", 1945 (Box 14, Folder 325)
    - "Leibniz's Theory of Science", 1946 (Box 14, Folder 326)
    - "Education for Intercultural Understanding", 1947 (Box 14, Folder 327)
    - "The Scientific Method for Determining the Correct Ends of Social Action", 1947 (Box 14, Folder 328)
    - "Towards a Bill (Declaration) of Rights for the United Nations", 1947 (Box 14, Folder 329)
    - "Alfred North Whitehead", 1948 (Box 14, Folder 330)
    - "The Idea of God as Affected by Modern Knowledge", 1948 (Box 14, Folder 331)
    - "The Neurological and Behavioristic Psychological Basis of the Ordering of Society by Means of Ideas", 1948 (Box 14, Folder 332)
    - Review of: A Concise History of the Law of Nations by Arthur Nussbaum, 1948 (Box 14, Folder 333)
    - "Einstein's Conception of Science", 1949 (Box 14, Folder 334)
    - "Introduction" to The Sociology of Knowledge of, Karl Mannheim and Pitirim A. Sorokin by Jacques Maquet, 1949 (Box 14, Folder 335)
    - "Jurisprudence in the Law School Curriculum", 1949 (Box 14, Folder 336)
    - La Filosofia y el Arto Contemporáneo, 1949 (Box 14, Folder 337)
    - "La Filosofia y un Orden Juridico Mundial", 1949 (Box 14, Folder 338)
    - "Methodology and Epistomology, Oriental and Occidental," delivered at 2nd East-West Philosophers' Conference, 1949 (Box 14, Folder 339)
    - "The Philosophy of Culture and its Bearing on the Philosophy of History", 1949 (Box 14, Folder 340)
    - remarks before Cuyahaga County Bar Association, 1949 (Box 14, Folder 341)
    - "The Difficulty in Relating the Diverse Spiritual Values of the Orient and the Occident", 1950 (Box 14, Folder 342)
    - "The Generic and Differentiating Factors in Pan American Culture", 1950 (Box 14, Folder 343)
    - "Naturalistic and Cultural Foundations for a more Effective International Law", 1950 (Box 14, Folder 344)
    - "The Problem of Integrating Knowledge and the Method for Its Commission", 1950 (Box 14, Folder 345)
    - "The Role of the Philosopher and in Particular the Philosophy of Culture in Preserving Intellectual Freedom and Understanding in the Contemporary World," delivered at UNESCO Round Table, 1950 (Box 14, Folder 346)
    - "Underhill Moore's Legal Science: It's Nature and Significance", 1950 (Box 14, Folder 347)
    - "The Absolute and the Non-Absolute in Scientific Knowledge", 1950 (Box 14, Folder 348)
    - "Asian Mentality and United States Foreign Policy", 1951 (Box 14, Folder 349)
    - "Crucial Events and Asian Images of the United States," seminar at Wenner-Gren Foundation, 1951 (Box 14, Folder 350)
    - "Human Law and the Laws of Nature in China and the West", 1951 (Box 14, Folder 351)
    - "Importance of Deductively Formulated Theory in Ethics and Social and Legal Science", 1951 (Box 15, Folder 352)
    - "The Mind of Asia", 1951 (Box 15, Folder 353)
    - "Philosophical Anthropology and World Law", 1951 (Box 15, Folder 354)
    - "The Relation Between Eastern and Western Philosophy", 1951 (Box 15, Folder 355)
    - "The Character of Western Knowledge", 1952 (Box 15, Folder 356)
    - "Concerning UNESCO's Basic Document on World Philosophy", 1952 (Box 15, Folder 357)
    - "Contemporary Jurisprudence and International Law", 1952 (Box 15, Folder 358)
    - "Obstacles to a World Legal Order and Their Removal", 1952 (Box 15, Folder 359)
    - "The Philosophy of Natural Science and Comparative Law", 1952 (Box 15, Folder 360)
    - "Philosophy's Statement of the Problem of Creativity", 1952 (Box 15, Folder 361)
    - Review of: Human Law and the Laws of Nature in China and the West by Joseph Needham, 1952 (Box 15, Folder 362)
    - Round table discussion: "What Should Be the Relation of Morals to Law?", 1952 (Box 15, Folder 363)
    - "The Unity and Dynamics of a Culture", 1952 (Box 15, Folder 364)
    - "American Education and African Culture", 1953 (Box 15, Folder 365)
    - Radio interview re: "Attorney General Brownell's Chicago Speech Raise Issue of Presidential Responsibility", 1953 (Box 15, Folder 366)
    - Review of: Natural Law Institute Proceedings, vol.V, ed. by Edward F. Barrett, 1953 (Box 15, Folder 367)
    - "Science and World Peace" address at Case Institute of Technology, 1953 (Box 15, Folder 368)
    - "Conversations With a Great Philosopher," review of: Dialogues of Alfred North Whitehead, 1954 (Box 15, Folder 369)
    - "International Conflict and Means of Resolution", 1954 (Box 15, Folder 370)
    - "Mathematical Physics and Korzybski's Semantics", 1954 (Box 15, Folder 371)
    - "The Method and Some Findings of Anthropological Jurisprudence," review of: The Law of Primitive Man by E. Adamson Hoebel, 1954 (Box 15, Folder 372)
    - "A New Approach to Human Nature", 1954 (Box 15, Folder 373)
    - "Psychological and Ideological Sources of International Conflict", 1954 (Box 15, Folder 374)
    - "Should the U.S. Give Military Aid to Pakistan?", 1954 (Box 15, Folder 375)
    - "The Struggle for Order and Progress: An Ideological Approach", 1954 (Box 15, Folder 376)
    - "United States' Foreign Policy and Continental European Union", 1954 (Box 15, Folder 377)
    - "Comparative Religion Today", 1955 (Box 15, Folder 378)
    - "Ethical Relativism in the Light of Recent Legal Science", 1955 (Box 15, Folder 379)
    - "Man's Relation to the Earth in its Bearing on His Aesthetic, Ethical and Legal Values", 1955 (Box 15, Folder 380)
    - "The Nineteenth Century Background of Contemporary Events", 1955 (Box 15, Folder 381)
    - Les Relations de la Grande-Bretagne Avec le Continent, Considérées à la Lumière de L'Union Européenne, 1955 (Box 15, Folder 382)
    - "Sources of Social Tension", 1955 (Box 15, Folder 383)
    - "Man's Role in Changing the Face of the Earth", 1956 (Box 15, Folder 384)
    - "The Method and Some Findings of Anthropological Jurisprudence," review of: The Law of Primitive Man by E. Adamson Hoebel, 1956 (Box 15, Folder 385)
    - "Petrazycki's Psychological Jurisprudence: Its Originality and Importance", 1956 (Box 15, Folder 386)
    - "Philosophy in the Contemporary World", 1956 (Box 15, Folder 387)
    - "Comments by Northrop at N.Y.U. Institute of Philosophy Conference, 1957 (Box 16, Folder 388)
    - "The Meeting of Civilization", 1957 (Box 16, Folder 389)
    - "Neutralism and United States Foreign Policy", 1957 (Box 16, Folder 390)
    - "Philosophical Issues in Contemporary Law", 1957 (Box 16, Folder 391)
    - "The Mediational Approval Theory of Law in American Legal Realism", 1958 (Box 16, Folder 392)
    - "The Nature of Modern Technology", 1958 (Box 16, Folder 393)
    - Review of: Sovereignty. An Inquiry Into the Political Good by Bertrand de Jouvenel, 1958 (Box 16, Folder 394)
    - Review of: The Tao of Science by R.C.H. Siu, 1958 (Box 16, Folder 395)
    - "Comparative Philosophy and Science in the light of Comparative Law", 1959 (Box 16, Folder 396)
    - "Cultural and Social Factors in National Strength: the United States", 1959 (Box 16, Folder 397)
    - "Cultural Mentalities and Medical Science", 1959 (Box 16, Folder 398)
    - "What Kind of American Civilization Do We Want", 1959 (Box 16, Folder 399)
    - "The Comparative Philosophy of Comparative Law", 1960 (Box 16, Folder 400)
    - Convocation address at Trinity College, 1960 (Box 16, Folder 401)
    - "The Challenge of the World Today", 1961 (Box 16, Folder 402)
    - "The Human Communicants in Communication Engineering", 1961 (Box 16, Folder 403)
    - "Introduction" to A Whiteheadian Aesthetic by Donald W. Sherburne, 1961 (Box 16, Folder 404)
    - "Comparative Philosophy and Science in the Light of Comparative Law", 1962 (Box 16, Folder 405)
    - "Comparative Philosophy and World Law", 1962 (Box 16, Folder 406)
    - "The Electro-Dynamic Theory of Life," with H.S. Burr, 1962 (Box 16, Folder 407)
    - Introduction to Man, Nature and God, 1962 (Box 16, Folder 408)
    - Review of: The Nature of Man and the Meaning of Existence by Harold Saxton Burr, 1962 (Box 16, Folder 409)
    - "The Scholar's Role in the Present Crisis", 1962 (Box 16, Folder 410)
    - "Towards a Deductively Formulated and Operationally Verifiable Comparative Cultural Anthropology", 1962 (Box 16, Folder 411)
    - "Prologue", 1963 (Box 16, Folder 412)
    - "The Relation Between the Natural and Normative Sciences", 1963 (Box 16, Folder 413)
    - "The Present Context and Character of the World's Religions", 1964 (Box 16, Folder 414)
    - "The Undifferentiated Aesthetic Continuum", 1964 (Box 16, Folder 415)
    - "Philosophic Foundations of Humanitarianism", 1965 (Box 16, Folder 416)
    - "The Wedding of the World's Civilizations", 1965 (Box 16, Folder 417)
    - "Commentary on Theological Resources From the Physical Sciences", 1966 (Box 17, Folder 418)
    - "The Present Context and Character of the World's Religions", 1966 (Box 17, Folder 419)
    - "Philosophy and World Civilization", 1967 (Box 17, Folder 420)
    - "Preface" to "The Political Imperative: The Corporate Character of Unions", 1968 (Box 17, Folder 421)
    - "The Rationally Analytic and Impressionistically Concrete Components of Western Music", 1971 (Box 17, Folder 422)
    - "The Self-Contradictory Character of Introspective and Non-Cognitive Meta-Ethical Theories", 1971 (Box 17, Folder 423)
    - "The Deeper Meaning and Promise of Today's Events", 1973 (Box 17, Folder 424)
    - "The Source of Swami Akhilanda's Remarkable Influence", 1974 (Box 17, Folder 425)
    - Can Interpersonal Neurophysiological Relations be Rigoriously Defined Mathematically..., with José Simoes da Fonseca, 1975 (Box 17, Folder 426)
    - "Contemporary Einsteinian Epistemology and Neoplatonic Christianity", 1979 (Box 17, Folder 427)
    - "Instruments and Ideals", undated (Box 17, Folder 428)
    - "Linguistic Symbols and Legal Norms", undated (Box 17, Folder 429)
    - "The Neurophysiological Meaning of Culture", undated (Box 17, Folder 430)
    - "Philosophy and World Peace", undated (Box 17, Folder 431)
    - "The Practical Consequences of Legal Positivism in the United States, Free India and Canada" (unpublished), undated (Box 17, Folder 432)
    - Review of: Asia and Western Dominance by K.M. Panikkar, undated (Box 17, Folder 433)
    - "Scientific Method and Social Problems" (unpublished), undated (Box 17, Folder 434)
- RESEARCH MATERIAL, 1942-1961; Series III; 1.50 linear feet (4 boxes)
  RESEARCH MATERIAL is arranged alphabetically by country, region, or subject. Within each file the material is roughly sorted by date.
  - Africa, 1950-1959 (Box 18, Folder 435-436)
  - Anthropology, undated (Box 18, Folder 437)
  - Asia, 1952-1955 (Box 18, Folder 438)
  - Australia, 1945-1954 (Box 18, Folder 439)
  - Austria, 1952 (Box 18, Folder 440)
  - The Balkans, 1952-1953 (Box 18, Folder 441)
  - Bolivia, 1952 (Box 18, Folder 442)
  - Brazil, 1952 (Box 18, Folder 443)
  - Canada, 1952-1954 (Box 18, Folder 444)
  - Ceylon, 1952, 1956 (Box 18, Folder 445)
  - China, 1952-1956 (Box 18, Folder 446)
  - Communism, 1949-1952 (Box 18, Folder 447-448)
  - Communism and economics, 1942-1952 (Box 18, Folder 449)
  - Communism, nature of, 1952 (Box 18, Folder 450)
  - Cuba, 1953 (Box 18, Folder 451)
  - Cultural resurgence, 1950-1954 (Box 18, Folder 452)
  - Dominican Republic, 1953 (Box 18, Folder 453)
  - Economics, 1949-1952 (Box 18, Folder 454)
  - Egypt, 1952-1956 (Box 19, Folder 455)
  - France, 1953-1960 (Box 19, Folder 456-458)
  - Germany, 1950-1959 (Box 19, Folder 459-462)
  - Great Britain, 1951-1954 (Box 19, Folder 463)
  - Guatemala, 1952 (Box 19, Folder 464)
  - Holland, 1952 (Box 19, Folder 465)
  - India, 1942-1952 (Box 19, Folder 466)
  - India, 1952-1956 (Box 20, Folder 467-468)
  - Indo China, 1953-1954 (Box 20, Folder 469)
  - Islam, 1950-1954, undated (Box 20, Folder 470-471)
  - Italy, 1951-1954 (Box 20, Folder 472)
  - Japan, 1948-1952 (Box 20, Folder 473)
  - Korea, 1953-1958 (Box 20, Folder 474)
  - Latin America, 1952 (Box 20, Folder 475)
  - Lawrence, David, 1953 (Box 20, Folder 476)
  - Lippmann, Walter, 1953-1954 (Box 20, Folder 477)
  - Luxembourg, 1951, 1954 (Box 20, Folder 478)
  - McCarthy affair, 1954 (Box 20, Folder 479)
  - Mexico, 1952-1953 (Box 20, Folder 480)
  - Miscellaneous, 1952-1955, undated (Box 20, Folder 481)
  - Pakistan, 1954-1961 (Box 20, Folder 482)
  - Palestine, 1952-1953 (Box 21, Folder 483)
  - Peru, 1948-1954 (Box 21, Folder 484)
  - Philippines, 1952, 1955 (Box 21, Folder 485)
  - Philosophy of Law, 1950 (Box 21, Folder 486)
  - Religion, 1952-1954 (Box 21, Folder 487)
  - Religion, Roman Catholic, 1952-1953 (Box 21, Folder 488)
  - Russia, 1949-1959 (Box 21, Folder 489-491)
  - The Saar, 1954-1955 (Box 21, Folder 492)
  - Socialism, 1951 (Box 21, Folder 493)
  - Spain, 1952-1953 (Box 21, Folder 494)
  - Tunisia, 1957 (Box 21, Folder 495)
  - Turkey, 1953 (Box 21, Folder 496)
  - United Nations, 1948-1953 (Box 21, Folder 497)
  - United States, 1952-1956 (Box 21, Folder 498-499)
  - Unity, European, 1948-1953 (Box 21, Folder 500)
  - Venezuela, 1953 (Box 21, Folder 501)
- WRITINGS OF OTHERS, 1915-1972; Series IV; 6.75 linear feet (17 boxes)
  Series IV, WRITINGS OF OTHERS, contains copies of articles and books given to Northrop. The material is arranged alphabetically by surname and then chronologically.
  - Akesson - Del Vecchio, 1957-1971, undated (Box 22, Folder 502-512)
  - D'Entrèves - Grebe, 1928-1972, undated (Box 23, Folder 513-530)
  - Grebe - Kluckhohn, 1922-1971, undated (Box 24, Folder 531-549)
  - Laszlo - MacKay, 1931-1971, undated (Box 25, Folder 550-570)
  - McKeon - Mead, 1932-1967, undated (Box 26, Folder 571-592)
  - Means - Myhill, 1912-1964, undated (Box 27, Folder 593-624)
  - Nahm - Page, 1929-1971, undated (Box 28, Folder 625-666)
  - Pap - Quesada, 1926-1969, undated (Box 29, Folder 667-700)
  - Rahder - Ritter, 1928-1971, undated (Box 30, Folder 701-725)
  - Ritter - Ryu, 1929-1965, undated (Box 31, Folder 726-752)
  - Sagar - Shankland, 1934-1963, undated (Box 32, Folder 753-777)
  - Sheffer - Sprinkle, 1923-1967, undated (Box 33, Folder 778-802)
  - Stebbing - Thomson, 1926-1961, undated (Box 34, Folder 803-831)
  - Thurston - Wagner, 1925-1961, undated (Box 35, Folder 832-853)
  - Wagner de Rayna - White, 1931-1968, undated (Box 36, Folder 854-875)
  - Whorf - Wuthenau, 1915-1968, undated (Box 37, Folder 876-893)
  - Wyman - Zilsel, 1928-1960, undated (Box 38, Folder 894-905)
  - List of books and articles given to F.S.C. Northrop bearing an inscription (Box 38, Folder 906)
- PERSONAL PAPERS, 1914-1972; Series V; 4.75 linear feet (8 boxes)
  All materials in PERSONAL PAPERS are arranged alphabetically by subject and then chronologically. Box 46 contains oversize items.
  - Address book, undated (Box 39, Folder 907)
  - Australia and Hawaii trip, 1949 (Box 39, Folder 908)
  - Awards
    See also: box 46, folders 986-987
    - The Society of Sigma Xi, 1945 (Box 39, Folder 909)
    - Honorary degree Beloit College, 1946 (Box 39, Folder 910)
    - Honorary degree The University of Hawaii, 1949 (Box 39, Folder 911)
    - Mexican government, 1949 (Box 39, Folder 912)
    - Honorary degree Rollins College, 1955 (Box 39, Folder 913)
    - Hamilton Holt Award, 1960 (Box 39, Folder 914)
    - Honorary degree Pratt Institute, 1961 (Box 39, Folder 915)
    - Wenner-Gren Foundation, 1964 (Box 39, Folder 916)
    - Wilbur Lucius Cross medal, 1968 (Box 39, Folder 917)
    - Wilbur Clyde Devane award, 1968 (Box 39, Folder 918)
  - Beginning Cantonese: studied by the Northrops 1919-1920, undated (Box 39, Folder 919)
  - Bookplates, undated (Box 39, Folder 920)
  - Christmas card lists, 1958, undated (Box 39, Folder 921)
  - Contracts, 1948-1966 (Box 39, Folder 922)
  - Correspondence, 1914-1945 (Box 39, Folder 923-930)
  - Correspondence, 1946-1962, undated (Box 40, Folder 931-933)
  - Degrees
    See: box 46, folder 988
  - Italian trip, 1957 (Box 40, Folder 934)
  - Invitations and programs, 1929-1972, undated (Box 40, Folder 935-939)
  - Johnston, John Walter, 1914 (Box 40, Folder 940)
  - Journals, 1943-1953 (Box 40, Folder 941-944)
  - The Meeting of East and West: publicity, 1946 (Box 41, Folder 945)
  - Memberships, 1930-1954 (Box 41, Folder 946)
    See also: box 46, folder 991
  - Miscellaneous, 1930-1972, undated (Box 41, Folder 947)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1929-1962, undated (Box 41, Folder 948-952)
  - Northrop, Christine Johnston
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 41, Folder 953)
    - World War I clippings, 1918 (Box 41, Folder 954)
    - World War I identification and orders, 1918-1919 (Box 41, Folder 955)
    - World War I memorabilia, 1918-1919 (Box 41, Folder 956)
    - World War I pictures, 1918-1919 (Box 41, Folder 957)
    - World War II volunteer service, 1941-1942, undated (Box 41, Folder 958)
  - Northrop, Filmer Stuart Cuckow, 1940-1962, undated (Box 41, Folder 959)
  - Northrop, Filmer Stuart Cuckow: identification, 1919 (Box 41, Folder 960)
  - Northrop, Stuart Johnston, 1933-1934, undated (Box 41, Folder 961)
  - Other travels, 1951-1957 (Box 41, Folder 962)
  - Photograph albums
    - Ceylon, India, and Spain, undated (Box 41, Folder 963)
    - Western Europe, undated (Box 42, Folder 964)
    - Europe and Asia, undated (Box 42, Folder 965)
    - Latin America, undated (Box 43, Folder 966)
  - Photographs
    See also: box 46, folder 992
    - India, Circa1950 (Box 43, Folder 967)
    - Miscellaneous, 1918-1965, undated (Box 43, Folder 968)
    - Silliman College, undated (Box 43, Folder 969)
    - Yale University, undated (Box 43, Folder 970)
  - Reviews (Box 43, Folder 971)
    - The Complexity of Legal and Ethical Experience, 1960 (Box 43, Folder 971)
    - European Union and United States Foreign Policy, 1954 (Box 43, Folder 972)
    - Ideological Differences and World Order, 1949 (Box 43, Folder 973)
    - The Logic of the Sciences and Humanities, 1949 (Box 43, Folder 974)
    - The Meeting of East and West, 1946 (Box 43, Folder 975)
    - Philosophical Anthropology and Practical Politics, 1960 (Box 43, Folder 976)
    - Science and First Principles, 1931-1932 (Box 43, Folder 977)
    - Sound recordings
      See: box 46, folders 994-995
  - South Asia trip, 1950 (Box 43, Folder 978)
  - Yale University, 1932-1966 (Box 43, Folder 979)
    - Exams and syllabi, 1935-1955 (Box 43, Folder 980)
    - Silliman College, 1940-1948, undated (Box 43, Folder 981)
    - Silliman College scrapbooks, 1940-1941 (Box 44, Folder 982-983)
  - YMCA: memorabilia, Circa1919-1921 (Box 44, Folder 984)
  - YMCA: bills and receipts, 1920, undated (Box 44, Folder 985)
  - Cards for books in the library of F.S.C. Northrop and bibliography cards, undated (Box 45, Folder 985)
  - Oversize
    - Awards: Freedom House, Willkie Memorial Building Award, 1953 (Box 46, Folder 986)
    - Awards: Pratt Institute, honorary degree, 1961 (Box 46, Folder 987)
    - Degrees, 1918-1924 (Box 46, Folder 988)
    - Tepotzotlan by E.W. Hathoway, 1941 (Box 46, Folder 989)
    - The Meeting of East and West: illustrations, Circa1946 (Box 46, Folder 990)
    - Memberships: American Academy of Arts and Sciences, 1951 (Box 46, Folder 991)
    - Photographs, 1917-1921 (Box 46, Folder 992)
    - Rollins College founders week, 1960 (Box 46, Folder 993)